各位请跟我到另一房间
This way please, we'll go to the next room
这里有一幅名为赫林之女仆的名画
Here, there was a painting by Trouillebeut called "Harem's Servant"
在不久之前被盗窃了
It was stolen a few weeks ago
所以这老馆长非常伤心
That's why our director is so upset
他天天在这里等待着
He is waiting here everyday
希望有一天 能有奇迹出现
Hoping that miracle will happen
名画会再出现
The painting will be re-appear
大家请跟我往那边走
Please follow me to another room
你喜欢这画家吗
Do you like this painting?
喜欢 失去了真可惜
Oh yes, quite a lot!
不用客气
No, thanks!
好
Good
小姐 你没事吧
Miss, are you alright?
有什么可以帮忙吗
Does it hurt? Please sit down
小姐 你不可以坐在这个箱子上面
No Miss, you can't sit on this box
里边有幅画好贵重的
There's a very valuable painting inside
蒙娜丽莎
MonaLisa?
不是
No it's not,
是一幅叫做“珍夏梦布丹”的名画
it's a Modigliani portrait
很名贵的 请你尽快起来
Please sit elsewhere, or I'll get into trouble
好 好
OK...OK...
她的鞋子修好了吗 箱子要小心啊
Miss here, your shoe is fixed
很名贵的请你尽快起来
There's a very valuable
小姐 我帮你修好了
Miss please, I'm serious
谢谢
Thanks!
再见
Bye
GIGI 早安
GiGi. Good morning
谢谢
Thanks!
唔 今天的香水特别香 一定是名牌
Today's perfume is so fragrant, must be fantastic!
我喷了整瓶的香水在那名画的箱子上
I almost used the whole bottle
嗯 谢谢 另外再给你买一支
I'll buy you another at Lafayette!
来块点心
Give me a dimsum first
你小心来不及
Well jurry, time is running out
你赶时间吗
What's the hurry?
你正经一点行不行
Don't interrupt me
我不赶时间 天还没黑呢
I'm in no hurry, it's not dark yet
GI GI
Gi Gi!
你这个人老是吊儿郎当的
You're just a big baby
法国这个地方就最合你了
France is the best place for you
真的
Yeah!
还有法国女人
Especially French women
GI GI
Gi Gi!
你知道那是什么地方吗
Do you know what that is?
知道 大众妈妈院嘛
Of course! It's Naughty Dame!
那是巴黎圣母院呀
Of course not! It's Notre-Dame!
真希望可以在那举行婚礼
I always wanted to get married there
很多花童花女陪我一起走进教堂
with those little boys and girls...
整条路上铺满了牵牛花
along the aisle throwing morning glories
关上车门 出发
Close the door, let's go
你认得我吗
Do you know me?
不
No
我的名字叫阿真 谢谢
My name is James, thanks
我是通天大盗 明天看报纸吧
I'm notorious thief, read tomorrow papers
你看那架车
Look at that car!
前面那对男女真热情呀
Hey! Did you see what they're doing there?
现在的年青人什么都做得出
Youngsters these days do anything they want
踩着油门向前 抓稳方向盘
Step on the gas, get closer, take it
帮帮忙 快接近啊
Hey, be a pal and help me out?
记住呀 香水
Remember, the perfume!
接我的时候一定要用慢档
Don't forget to drive in lowgear when you collect me
知道啦
Don't worry Don't forget!
走吧
Go away
闻不到啊 奇怪
I don't smell a thing, how come?
呜啊 什么香水这么臭啊
Jeez, the perfume stinks
臭过他妈的尿
More than a horse's, shit!
啊 过期香水
Oh, the perfume must be too old
停止 妈的
Freeze, shit!
咦 货卡发生什么事呢
Hey, what's going up there?
嗨 阿贵 他下来了 我去接他
Hey, Joe is coming
哦
Oh
哎
Let's go get him, come on
喂 过来
Hey, over here, hurry
过来呀 这边
Hey, over here
收油
Slow down
踩车闸
Almost there
低档啊 三八
Lowgear, stupid broad
我捉到他了 捉到他了
I got him, I got him
收油啊 哎呀
Slow down, slow down
喂 喂 停车 停车啊
Hey, stop, stop the car
停车呀
stop the car
你这死三八 哇 日你奶奶的
You goddam stupid broad
阿海 怎么样 摔伤了没有
Joe, you alright,
痛不痛啊 啊
are you hurt, painful?
咦 哎哟 算了
Yeah, does it hurt?
算了 你说这样痛不痛
Alright enough
干什么嘛
Well?
我教你几百次了
How many times did I tell?
开车不要死用一个档嘛
Don't just drive in lowgear
有时候用一 有时候用二
Sometimes use the first gear, sometimes the second
叫你踩闸又不踩 叫你加油又不加
You never do what I tell you!
叫你减油又不减 真是个大笨猪啊
You're a brainless bimbo
我怎么知道要用什么档啊
I never know how you want it
空档
I want it off
你去哪
Where are you going?
交水费
Water the plant
阿贵 开车用什么档
Hey, you said never start the car in which gear?
低档
Drive!
低呀 哦
开车咯
Well drive!
啊 喂
Hey...Hey...
再见
Bye-bye
你们两个这么做是没有好结果的
You two will regret this
去吧 你们尽管去吧
Go on, leave,
祝你们春梦了无痕啊
I hope you get what you desert
朱生 你知道嘛
Mr Chu, do you know...
最近我国的名画时常给人盗窃
some of our famous paintings has been stolen lately,
虽然 我们是非常欢迎全世界的人
we of course welcome those who come all over the world...
来法国欣赏我国的艺术
to appreciate our art,
但绝对不希望是来取走的
but just hope they don't take them away from us
我们查过
We've done save investigations,
怀疑偷画的人是中国人
and we suspect that the thieves are Chinese,
而且与
from an...
香港庞大的偷画集团关系密切
underground painting collector.
你们三个要永远记住
You three remember,I raised you
你们全都是我捡回来养的 吃我的 穿我的
I fed you, clothed you Now you got to listen to me
什么都要听我的
From now on
我就教你们怎么样赚钱
I'll teach you how to make a living
吶 这就叫做明眼手快 阿贵
Joe, I'll teach you to be sharp of eye and quick of hand
过来 哦 我就站在公共汽车上 过来
I'm now in a bus, come here
怎么了 你通了电啦
What's the matter? You crazy?
汽车 不是在开动吗
Nothing, the bus ride is jumpy!
过那边 哦
Then go over there
嘿嘿
Oh
岂有此理
Godam it
左偷右偷都偷不到 你真是个大饭桶
You'll never learn, you doestn't worth anything
你整天哭是不是 扫把星
You're crying all the time Brings me bad luck
你想食饭吶 你别做梦了
No food for you
红豆 喝汤啊
Cherie, let's eat
刚才洒的我裤子全湿啦
I stained my pants because of you
我留了饭给你吃
I stole food for you
吃饭吧
Eat
好啊 吃啊 吃啊
Go on, eat
Eat
饿坏了吧 好不好吃啊 别吃太急
You must be hungry, eat up
希望你们香港警方能与我们合作
We hope that the Hong Kong police will cooperate with the French Investigators
捉拿这些盗贼吧
in stopping this crime
红豆 你过去扮要饭的
Cherie, you be the beggar
又是我呀
Me again?
去呀
Go on
你 去那边
Go over there
好
OK
可怜可怜我呀 给我面包吧
Uncle can you give me some bread please
我好几天没有吃饭啦
I haven't eaten in days, please
没有啊 快走啊 臭要饭的
Go away, beggar
来 快走开 别妨碍我做生意啊
Don't bother me
给我面包吧
Please don't, please
可怜我呀
Go away
哎唷 你敢抽我屁股
Hey, you hit me
不是我呀 不是我呀
It's not me, it's not me
快走开
Go?
喂 还说不是你
You still deny it?
真的不是我 不是我呀
Really, it's not me
别捣乱 快走开
Let's get out of here
喂 你偷我的面包
You stole my bread
喂 快走
Hey, let's split
这是谁教你的 啊
You're so young, who taught you to steal?
你不要走呀
Stop!
红豆 快跑
Cherie, run!
还想走呀 小偷
You still want to run?
警察快抓住他们 他们三个偷我面包
Those three kids stole my bread, get them
阿婆啊 别着急 没人会抢你的
Lady, slow down, no one will take your bread away
有我们看着呢
We'll keep a look out
阿婆 好不好吃呀
Lady, is it good?
好吃
Very good
阿婆 你慢慢吃
Take your time,
多吃点啊
have more
哎 别跑 别跑
Hold it, come back
干什么 来来 回来
It hurts. come back
不关我们的事啊
What do you want? I didn't do anything
你不要抓他们
Don't catch them
我没有偷东西 不用怕
We didn't do anything? Don't worry,
不关我事 叔叔不会抓你们的
We're innocent I won't arrest you
我想 你们也都饿了吧
Well? You must be starving
是啊
Yeah
天气冷了 拿着去买件衣服
It's getting cold, get some clothes
哇 谢谢干爹
Thank you, Papa Thanks,papa
我没说收你们当干儿子
When did I become your papa?
有的吃就是干爹嘛 是啊
Whenever you gave us food
对啊 全世界就你一个人对我们最好了
You're the only one who has been nice to us
你们很肯帮助人 也是好人啊
You're not so bad yourselves
干脆你们长大了去考警察吧
Ever think of becoming policemen?
再说吧
Talk about it later
不一定要做警察才能帮助人啊
Don't have to be a policeman to help people
是啊 干爹
That's right, papa
总之 以后有什么困难就找叔叔
Whenever you're in trouble, come to me
不要再偷东西啦
Don't ever steal again
唔
Yes, sir
众里寻她千百度
How come the painter
蓦然回首
chose this lady as model
小妞已睡歪脖子
She looks like having a sprained neck
阿真 尝尝汤好不好喝
Jim, come and try the soup
熬了四个多小时 来
It's been boiling for 4 hours
怎么样
Well?
我不明白你熬了半天还是像罐头汤
Why does it taste like canned soup?
讨厌
Go to hell
恭祝你生日磕破头 还磕掉大门牙
Happy birthday to you
年年都要煮饭 岁岁都要熬汤
Happy birthday to dear Cherie
恭喜你
Happy birthday to you
恭喜你 你好漂亮哦
Congratulations, you look gorgeous
谢谢
Thanks!
吶 今天我生日 我说了算
Today's my birthday, you do what I say
生日大哥大
Your birthday doesn't mean you're the boss
喝了这杯香槟之后
After this glass of champagne,
我们以后不再做贼了
we stop stealing
是 都希望这样
All agreed?
现在到了吹蜡烛的时候
Hey, blow out the candles
吹呀
Hurry HP
哎 先许个愿
Hey hey, make a wish first
许呀 许呀
Go on, go
嗯
OK
我希望我们收山之后
I hope after we retire,
找一个太平的地方
we can live in peace
好咯 别说咯 蛋糕全凉咯
Look! That's enough, have some ice-cream!
哈哈哈 白毛女 白毛女
Hehe, Snow White, Snow White!
我帮你擦
Let me help you
你这次太过分了
Hey, you're going too fast
啊 要玩就要玩的痛快嘛
When I make a take, I go all the way
快去哄哄她
Make her feel better
哎 你也有份吶
Hey, that includes you too
她听你哄嘛
Come on, she listens to you
那我多糗啊
This is embarrassing
小小的红豆妹
Cherie, Cherie my love
你不是在生我阿海的气吧
Are you really mad at me?
你看 在水边的红豆
Look, my Cherie Amour
鹅蛋形的脸圆 哇塞 修长的上半身
You are my true loved one
那下半身就不必说咯
The only one I swear, bar none
你甜起来呢 会甜死人的
From head to foot need I say bun
你是一个非常非常会生养的优良品种
Beauty and charm is yours, to you I run
来
I'd never leave, even forced by gun
来嘛 红豆妹妹
I'd always want you, even if you were a nun
你爱浪漫没问题 我带你去浪漫
With you I know my search is done
你爱看戏 我带你去看戏
Only you bring my luck and lots of fun
你爱做明星 我带你去做明星
I'll love you always, as long as there is a sun
很多大导演都是我的好朋友
You are my true loved one
来 坐下去 不要害怕嘛
The only one I swear, bar none
坐下去嘛 坐呀
From head to foot need I say bun
我们演戏给自己看 我们演爱人
Beauty and charm is yours, to you I run
你是我的月亮 我的太阳 你叫我上刀山我就上刀山
I'd never leave, even forced by gun
叫我下火海我就下火海
I'd always want to you, even if you were a nun
要生我们一起生 要死我们一起死
With you I know my search is done
我爱你 你不爱我 我爱你 还是你先去死吧
Only you bring my luck and lots of fun
啊 我死啦
Ah, I'm drowning
啊 你要死啊 踢我下水
How dare you kick me?
我不是有意的 有东西射到我脚啦
It's not me, something hit my leg
还不拉我上去
Let me out of here
上来啊 上来
Come on
快走啊 还不快走 全都是你
Let's go, come on
臭小子 串通好了 整我 你别走
You fooled me with her! Don't go
阿贵 将来你老了
Joe, where do you want to be
去哪儿安度晚年啊
when you get old?
我住破茅屋也没关系
Anywhere is fine with me
不知道红豆怎么样 啊
But, how about you?
我最希望可以住个不打仗的地方
I first want to live in peace and quiet
伊拉克 伊拉克最太平啦
Iran is peaceful
不然就住上天堂
Heaven is pretty
天堂的空气最清新呀
peaceful too
讨厌
Assholes
我们东奔西跑
We're always on the move
真应该找一个地方落脚
We should try to find a place to settle down
诶 吉姆兄 话不能这么说
Yeah but that's not the point
正所谓千古江山 英雄无觅处
The Universe is endless, the Brave are always searching
舞谢歌台 风流总被雨打风吹去
For some happiness, however fleeting it may be
哎 真想念香港
Actually I miss Hong Kong
想马上回去吃碗馄饨面
I miss Wonton Noodles
我也怀念台南蛋仔面
And Yuen Long Cakes
深井的烧鹅 避风塘的虾蟹
Shen Zheng fued goose, Causeway Bay seafood
我忘不了香港的夜色
Sheung Wan's egg cakes
还有阿里山的日出也很浪漫
Also Stanley's jeans
阿里山地姑娘美如水呀 阿里山地少年壮如山
Yes, Queen's Rd East, Queen's Rd West
漂亮吗 漂亮
Isn't it gorgeous here? Yes
我先下去巡视一下业务
Let's check it out
青霞 丽君
Brigitte Barkot, Gina Lollo brigida
瞎嚷什么
What are you yelling at?
我想看看林青霞和邓丽君在不在
I just want to check if those two women were here
什么
What are you saying?
你没看报纸吗
Didn't you see the paper?
她们最喜欢到康城来 脱光了衣服游泳了
They said they always sunbathe here
我想找她们签个名嘛
I want their autograph
她们把衣服都脱光了 哪还有笔呀
How can they have pens if they're naked?
走啦
Let's go, DOM
我有啊
I have one!
宝叔
Hi!
你好吗
How are you?
你好红豆 你好
Hello Cherie Hello
欢迎名人阿真
Joe, Jim, welcome
你好
How are you
啊 什么这样的
Ah, how come?
多少钱
How much?
五十万
Half a million
太贵了
Too expensive,
这幅画不值这么多钱 四十万吧
the painting only worths 400,000
他说太贵了 四十万
He said it's too expensive, 400,000
帮我问候他亲爱的妈妈
Tell him he's a motherfucker
怎么说啊
What is he saying?
直说啊
Go on
我是想说这个 你妈妈在哪呢
I want to ask you "Where's your mother?"
我想问候她老人家
I want to say hello to her
她很好 多谢关心
She's fine, thank you very much
不用客气
You are welcome
告诉他一分也不能减
Tell him, not a penny less
五十万 他说可以
Half a million, no discount
完啦
OK, it's deal
五十万 他说好
Half a million, he agreed
好
VOILA Great
我出二百万美金
Steal this painting for me,
请你们帮我偷一幅画
I gave you 2 million
他说什么
Please translate. Thank you
他说你们偷到这幅画他给二百万
He offered you 2 million to steal a painting
哇 二百万
2 million?
你们说过不再偷了
But you both promised not to steal any more?
你曾经说过吗
Did I say that?
我好像没说过
I don't remember saying that
喂 你们不可以说话不算数啊
You can't break your promise
这幅画是存放在尼斯一个古堡内
This painting is in a castle in Nice
画的背后是有一个爱情故事的
There's also a love story attached to it
画中的女郎是画家的爱人
The lady in the painting was the painter's lover
那画家画完这幅画就死了
The painter died soon after finishing the painting
他的灵魂就附进这画里面
and it's haunted
所以此画很邪
by his soul
谁能偷到此画便能声名大噪
Any self-respecting thief would be proud to steal it,
但是画从来没有
but it's never...
离开过古堡
left the castle Whoever manages it will be famous for you it's a challenge
真他妈啰嗦 说什么呢
Such a long speech, what did he say?
我不想说
I don't want to tell you
说啊
Tell me
说哎
Tell us
他说这幅画很邪 谁偷到手谁就死
He said this painting is evil, whoever steals it will die
你们到底怎样 说啊
So what do we do?
哎
Hey!
怎么样
Well?
杀
Do it
Do it?
杀
啊
Ah...
对不起 我们已经决定退休了
Sorry, we've already retired
你们真的决定退休
Is that true?
问你们是不是真的有信心
He asked if you're sure you can do it?
当然 当然
Sure, Yeah... Yeah...
好吧 不做就算了 真可惜
OK, forget it, I'm really sorry
他说叫我们先走
He said we can go now
哎 不用收订金了吗
Hey, what about the deposit?
他说改天再联络
They will contact us
啊 那也喝一杯再走嘛
Hey, let's have a drink first
再见
Bye
多谢再见 再见
Thanks,bye
你一定会做的
It's working
老爷 香港长途电话
A call from Hong Kong, sir
谢谢 MR CHOW
Hello, Mr Chow!
喂 巴顿先生 有没有问题
Hello, Mr Burton, any problem?
没问题 他们会做的
No problem, just do it
十分好
Very good
红豆 见到阿真了吗
Cherie, did you see Jim?
不知道去哪了
I don't know where he went?
他的工具都不在 会不会是去
His "work" tools have disappeared too, do you think...
这小子
Shit!
不要去
Please don't go
他没有我怎么行呢
He can't do a thing without me
他不会有事
He'll be fine
我就怕他有事
I'm afraid he'll get into trouble
我就知道你会去
I knew you'd do this
你们俩最好平安回来
You two better come back safe and sound
哎 我现在就去 你收拾东西
I'm going, you go pack up
明天早上九点钟 是九点钟
Remember tomorrow morning 9 o'clock
你在康城的那个小机场等我们
Wait for me at Cannes airport
记着订好三张机票 是三张机票
Book 3 tickets, 3 tickets
又怎么样
And then what?
答应我 这是真正的最后一次
Promise me this will be the last time
哎呀 你好烦吶
You're such a pain!
你怎么会在这
What are you doing here?
没我怎么能成局呢
It takes turn to tango
哎 没这么容易 可能有机关
Hey, it's too quiet, must be traps
是啊 可能会乱箭齐飞
Yeah, like lots of trap-wires
或者埋了地雷了
and arrows
试试就知道了
Let's check it out
唔
Um
什么也没有
Nothing
石室的大门在这
Here's the stone gate,
开关在什么地方
wonder where is the switch?
通常最不起眼的地方就是装机关的地方
For sure it's well hidden
你说什么
What are you saying?
搞什么鬼 哎 这里每幅画都过千万
I don't believe it! They hid this precious painting here?
不可能酒这么便宜
These are all cheap wines!
装门锁
The hidden must be the most obvious
哎 这根好长呀
Hey, how come it's so long?
进去吧 哼哼
Let's go!
找到了
It's you
喂 看见了没有
Hey, did you see that?
喂
Hey
哎呀 糟糕 哪根呢
Damn, which one?
哎呀 原来这个东西是会缩回去的
Hey, it moved by itself
是啊
Yeah,yeah
会缩的
It goes back
快点呀
Hurry HP
看什么看
What is it?
哎哟 干什么嘛
What are you doing?
喂
Hey
这个地台就算没有红外线也有几千瓦特电
May not be laser beams, but electricity, yes!
忽然阴风阵阵啊
God, so windy
搞气氛嘛
It's for effect!
嗯
Come on
来
小心
Careful.
又一个
Another.
接着啊
Here OK
来
Come on
好
OK
小心点 想死啊
Hey, careful, want me to die
你怎么死重死重的啊
How come you're so heavy
今天没大便嘛 上去啊
I eat a lot. Pull me up
我叫你上去 你还下来
I said pull me up, not down Want me to die?
用了吃奶的力了
Hold tight
快上啊
Pull me up
你别放屁啊
Don't you fart
大点力
Harder
行了吗
Did you get it?
快了
Almost
碰到没有
Did you touch it?
碰到啦 再大点力
Yeah, harder
差一点
Almost got it
行啦
Got it
准备
Ready
好
OK
放
Go Let's go
你的臭鞋还要不要
Hey. Do you still want your shoes?
太棒了 是真迹
We made it, it's the real thing
我就快脑充血啦
My blood is all going to my head
怪了 怎么她的眼睛发青光在瞪着我啊
How come she is starring at me?
因为你头上戴着电筒嘛
It's your lamp's reflection
哦
Right
喂
Hey
干什么
What are you doing?
快来救我啊
Come help me
别急
OK
快点
Hurry
来
Come on
无惊无险 我们走
It's quiet here, let's go
杀机四伏啊
Looks like a trap to me
奇怪了 眼见明台清阶 何来杀机
Strange, so quiet, how could that be?
下回分解
Wait and see
好啊 酒逢知己千杯少
OK, here's to our friendship
话不投机半句多
There's no need for words
话可不能这么说 真兄
No, I mean that wine
酒乃穿肠之物啊
is made up preserved grapes
众人皆醉我独醒
Everyone is drunk, I alone am lucid
啊哈 高人高见
Wow, Surat guy
哎 这里
Hey, over here!
我看见了
I see it
喂
Hey...
过来呀
Come on
我帮你看着
I'll check it for you
你要看着呀
You better!
屁股啊
Hey, watch your ass
我屁股大嘛
I got a big one
剩下最后一条
There's one more
轻而易举 先喝为敬 干杯
Easy job, cheers
请
Cheers
哎 你今年贵庚啊
How old are you?
反正比你小
You should be older
看看谁的腰硬 嗯
See who's better?
来啊
Come on
快点
Hurry HP
行了
Alright
不要走呀 不要走 再走就开枪啦
Get them, don't let them escape
快上车
Quick get in
怎么样
You alright?
幸亏子弹进的不深
Lucky the bullet isn't in too deep
抬高手看看
Raise your arm
高一点
Higher
动动手指 抓紧拳头
Move your finger, make a fist
小意思 你顶得住的
No big deal, you'll make it
我们早就说好了 有事就一起上
I warned you not to try it alone
你却自己去干 好了 现在受伤了不是
You had to try, look at you now
我去偷这幅画不是为了那个法国人
I didn't do it for the French man
你不是为了伟大的艺术吧
Don't be so superior, you're no artist
对 我不是为了艺术
I know that
我是为了红豆的幸福
I did it for Cherie
红豆的幸福 不就是你的幸福
If you did it for Cherie, you did it for yourself
你的幸福 不就是我的幸福
If you did it for yourself, you did it for me
我的幸福 不就是大家的幸福
If you did it for me, you did it for us all
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我总觉得你对朋友
You treat friends
比对你喜欢的女人好
better than the woman you love
错 我对朋友和女人一样那么好
No, I treat them both the same
你对她好你再说一遍
Same? Say what? Are you sure?
我现在对她不好吗
You're saying I'm not
你整天把她当木偶一样扯来扯去
You treat her like an object
忽冷怱热 一会好一会坏
Sometimes good, sometimes bad
她对你多好 只是你不知道
You call that treating her right?
我真希望我是你
Do you know I'm jealous of you?
你想没想过她的将来和幸福
Did you ever think of her?
想过没有
Did you?
有时候太照顾别人的感受会失去自我的
If you think of someone else,
你知道吗
you loose yourself?
其实你们俩都了解我的性格
You both know how I am
我喜欢东走走西逛逛
I like to be footloose
我喜欢流浪
and care free
爱一个人 不一定要跟她一辈子的
Who says I'll spend the rest of my life with her?
我喜欢一朵花 未必一定要把它摘下来
If I like a flower, I don't have to pick it
我喜欢风 难道叫风停下来 你让我闻一闻
If I like the wind, I don't need to bag it
我喜欢云 难道叫云飘下来 来罩着我
If I like a cloud, I don't need to hold it
我爱海 难道我跳海
If I like the sea, I don't...
你又在说什么啊 我跟你说的是人
What are you talking about? I am talking about humans
你却说风啊 花啊 云啊什么的
What's that about wind, flowers, clouds...
我跟你说的是女人
I was talking about women
女人是要爱的 要人疼的
Women need to be loved, and cared for
我知道结了婚之后
I know after marriage,
我会失去民主 失去自由
no more freedom of Democracy
所以我追求的是那种一刹之间的 光辉
All I want are...flings!
难道你没听人家说过
Did you ever hear that?
刹那的光辉并不代表永恒吗
A fling is not forever
哎 你知不知道你在流血
Hey, do you know you're nlrrfinh?
你知不知道你在受伤啊
Do you know you're wounded?
那又怎么样 你说完了没有
So what? Are you finished?
说完了没有
Well?
说完了
That's it
说完了 是吧
Really?
怎么样 好点吗
Are you feeling better?
没事就走吧 红豆在机场等我们呢
If you're alright, let's go Cherie's waiting at the airport
杀了他们
Kill them,
一定要抢到那幅画 不能有失
get the painting whatever it takes
阿真 你先拿着画去机场 不要等我了
Jim, take the painting, don't wait for me
告诉红豆 我会去找她的
Tell Cherie I'll look for her
这里我顶着 快去机场找红豆
I'll hold them off, go to the airport
好
OK
波士 到了码头 我们会杀掉他
Boss, we're at the pier, will get them
岂有此理
Damn it!
阿真
Jim
阿真 还顺利吧 阿海呢 他在哪啊
Did you do it? Where's Joe?
阿真 你回答我啊 发生了什么事
Where is he? Jim, look at me, what happened?
怎么会这样
Huh, what's this?
我们出事了
We had some problem
我要去找他
I'll go look for him
不行 阿海 他死了
No, he's dead
走呀
Let's go
我要去找他
I want to find him
走呀
Come on
♪我劝你早点归去 ♪
♪你说你不想归去 只叫我抱着你 ♪
♪悠悠海风轻轻吹 冷却了野火堆 ♪
♪我看见伤心的你 ♪
♪你叫我怎舍得去 哭态也绝美 ♪
♪如何止哭 只得轻吻你发边 ♪
♪让风继续吹 ♪
♪不忍远离 ♪
♪心里极渴望 希望留下伴着你 ♪
♪风继续吹 ♪
♪不忍远离 ♪
♪心里极渴望 希望留下伴着你 ♪
♪过去多少 ♪
♪快乐记忆 ♪
♪何妨与你一起去追 ♪
♪要将忧郁苦痛洗去 ♪
♪柔情蜜意我愿记取 ♪
♪要强忍离情泪 ♪
♪未许它向下垂 ♪
♪愁如锁 眉头聚 ♪
♪别离泪 始终要下垂 ♪
♪我已令你快乐 ♪
♪你也令我痴痴醉 ♪
♪你已在我心 不必再问记着谁 ♪
♪留住眼内每滴泪 ♪
♪为何仍断续流默默垂 ♪
漂亮 这真是艺术
Beautiful... This is art
这是你的钱
Your money
我们有共同的爱好
We're two of a kind
大家都是为了钱呀 干得好
We both love the money, good work
谢谢
Thanks
你喜欢看看香港的夜色吗
Would you like to see the Hong Kong by night?
当然好啊
Sure, sure
带他去兜风
Yeah! show him around
我们会有人带你去兜兜风的
Someone will show you around
我的荣幸
Thank you!
听说香港的罪案日渐严重
I heard that the crime problem in H.K. is very serious
老爸
Dad, dad!
阿贵 原来你没死啊
Joe, you are still alive
你对脚
Your leg...
我也算命大 这么炸都没炸死
I am lucky, the explosion hasn't ended my life
我调查过了 是法国人背后搞鬼
It's all dad's fault, it must be the French man
我一定会解决它
I'll get him
你们大师兄从前身手很不错呀
Your brother used to be
能上山 能下水
the best in his field
哎 阿贵 有空陪老爸划划水吧
Joe, come and ski with me some time
如果你还能划水的话
If you still can
老爸 我从小到大都跟着你
Dad, I hope you'll think of me
没功劳也有苦劳啊
for old times sake
对 现在我变成废人
I'm useless now
你就当做善事 轻轻的扶我一把吧
Think of me as charity, give me a boost
阿贵 你现在这个样子
Joe, you know...
老爸看了真的很心疼啊
dad is pained to see you like this
可你叫我怎么扶你呢
but how do you want me to give you about?
儿子 你怎么样
Joe, are you OK?
你怎么样
Son, are you alright?
你这王八蛋 我现在告你蓄意伤人
You bastard, I'll sue you
哎 你不要乱说啊
Hey, don't talk nonsense
要告 就告这台阶蓄意伤人
If you must sue the staircase, it's what hurt you
你这个无赖
What?
哎 你们两个不要吵了
Stop yelling
这不关他的事 是我自己不小心
He's got nothing to do with, it's my fault
没出息 到现在还护着他
You're still protecting him?
吶 替他买张新轮椅
Buy him a new wheelchair
我先走了
I'm leaving
哎 我们俩哪吃得了这么多啊
Hey, how can you eat so much?
我不在的时候你可以自己弄东西吃嘛
So you can look for yourself when I'm not there
哎 不要让人家看见啊
Kick them over there
嗯 看见就麻烦了
Come on, help
啊
OK
那边还有呢
This is embarrassing
快 快点
Never mind them
可以了
Let's go
哎 我还有点事 你先回去吧
Hey, I'm busy, you go back first!
快点回来啊 帮我煮饭
Hurry back, I'll cook for you
带钱了吗
Do you have money?
带啦
Yeah!
嗨 阿真
Hi, Jim
红豆
Cherie
老爸 老爸
Dad Dad
哎呀 怎么了 弄伤了手了
Hey, what happened to your hand?
哦 皮外伤
Oh, nothing really
红豆 你怎么瘦了这么多啊
Cherie, why are you so thin?
没有啊
Not really
是不是 阿真不疼你啊
Doesn't Jim feed you well?
不是
Of course he does
阿真 你不是说要报答老爸吗
Jim, you said you wanted to pay me back
你说吧
What do you mean?
帮我偷幅画
Steal me that painting
什么画
What painting?
来 上来 来来
Come on, follow me, come on
这幅画怎么会在这
How come the painting is here
这个你别管
You don't need to know
它失踪了三年 就升值了三倍
It disappeared for 2 years, the price tripled
如果再失踪两年的话 你说吧 会升值多少钱吶
If it stayed losing 2 more years, how much will it worth then?
过些日子我会拿出来拍卖
I'll take it to the auction later
有阿贵帮你 容易多了
With Joe, it would be easy
可惜 他腿瘸了
Pity he lost his legs
他 他不是死了吗
Doesn't he die?
阿真见过他了 你没有跟他说吗
Jim saw him, didn't he mention it?
红豆 干爹
Cherie, Papa
嗨 干爹 有人找我 在外面
Somebody's looking for me? Outside?
阿海
Joe
嗨 好吗
How are you?
你以前喜欢到处去 现在习惯了
You used to travel a lot, do you miss it?
没什么分别
Nothing's different
其实我现在也可以到处去
I still travel, but around here
只不过现在世界小了一点 很平静的
My trips are smaller, quieter
比起外面的世界来 这里和平多了
But it's a lot more peaceful
带你去参观一下
I'll take you around
不要紧 我的腿早就没知觉了
Never mind, my legs don't feel a thing
来
Come on
这边是我的工作间
This is where I work,
前面是我的天文台
in front is my observatory
这是我的最新的电脑
This is my latest computer
没事的时候我就打游戏机玩
Whenever I can I play computer games
这是我的会客室
This is my guest's room
这是我新画的名画
This is my newest painting,
“在天愿为比翼鸟”
I call it "Bud's Paradise"
这是我的最新拍挡 它叫做宝宝
This is my newest partner, Bobo
宝宝叫HELLO 叫HELLO
Bobo, say Hello
HELLO HELLO
Hello! Hello!
这个是我画了三个月的壁画 漂亮吗
This wall painting took me 3 months, do you like it
平时我经常做运动的 你看
I still exercise a lot
这边是我的植物园
This side is my botanical Garden
这边是我的动物园
The other side is my zoo
里边所有的鸟都是从南非订回来的
All the birds are from South Africa
而坐在前面一脸严肃的人呢 就是我的恩人
The one sitting there looking serious is my benefactor
他姓干 名爹
He's like a father to me
拜拜
Bye
来 我带你去厨房看一看
Come on, I'll show you the kitchen
不用了 我这次来是找你帮忙的
No need, I just came to ask you a favor
什么事啊
What is it?
希望你去帮阿真
I want you to help James
阿真怎么啦
What's wrong with James?
他答应老爸做事
He promised Dad
上次跟你去偷画 已经受了伤
He would steal him the painting again
我担心他再出事
I'm afraid he'll get into trouble again
你帮帮他
Please help him
你们两个一直合作的很好
You two always work together
我不是不想帮
I want to help,
只是不知道他肯不肯让我帮
but does he want to be helped?
我知道你会帮 那我先走了
I knew you would, I'm leaving
再见
Bye
红豆妹妹
Cherie. Mou Amour
红豆妹妹 来
Come on, Cherie Mou Amour
它最近发神经病
He's depressed,
女朋友跟乌鸦飞走了
his girl friend eloped with a vulture
差一点跳楼
He almost killed himself
你还跟从前一样 一点也没有变
You haven't changed at all
宝宝 你没事就睡觉去吧
Bobo, if you want to sleep, then go to sleep
我的心早就裂了 你知不知道
I'm heart-broken, don't you know?
好 150万成交
Sold for the one point five million
MR．HAMUPTON 以150万
Mr Hamupton, for 1.5 million
得到这个明朝青花五指花瓶
Gets this Ming bottle
我们大家恭喜他
Congratulations
好
OK!
接着我们拍卖唐朝的五彩骆驼
Now we have Tang Camel Statue
就是在十五页的第六号
On p.15, no.6
这次慈善拍卖所得到的善款
This auction's proceeds go to
会捐给香港儿童伤残协会
the HK Handicapped Association
请各位踊跃投标
I hope you'll all contribute
底价是50万
Starting price, five hundred thousand
好了 为善最乐
OK, no long faces,
请大家不要令场面冷落
this is for charity
请留步 没有被邀请不能够进去
Sir, you can only enter on invitation
啊 对不起
Really? Sorry I didn't know
好 60万 70万
Good, 600 thousand, 700 thousand
70万 70万 现在是70万
Now 700 thousand, 700 thousand... who says more?
老周啊 你那幅 很热门啊
Mr. Chow, your painting is popular,
下次拍卖价钱一定吓死人
it'll sell Well
那当然了
I know,
你们的保安系统有没有问题呀 我那幅画买了超保险了
but is your security safe?
放心吧 你那幅画放在我们的保险库绝无问题 我信你
Of course, your painting is safe with us. I trust you.
好 各位
Alright, who give more than
有没有超过110万的 高抬贵手
1.1 million thousand?
有没有 有没有
Anyone, anyone?
120万 130万
1.2 million, 1.3 million...
接着是140万 好 140万
Alright, 1.4 million one,
140万 一 140万 二
1.4 million two...
喔 在那遥远的那方
On the far side of the room,
令人兴奋的事情出现了
something wonderful
150万
1.5 million
有没有高过150万的
Who says more, 1.5 million,
150万
1.5 million
160万
OK. 1.6 million...come on...
现在是160万 请大家反应热烈一点
Keep on, 1.6 million, 1.7 million...
哦 170万 哦 真是太好了
1.7 million, alright
残而不废的年青人 你真是令我感动
You're not a useless handicapped, I'm impressed
老爸 看看你有什么表示
Can you guys do any better? Dad,
你又在扮慈善家
you're just pretending to be charitable
哦 好极了 180万
OK. 1.8 million, 1.8 million
190万
1.9 million,
你猜这里的人知不知道 是200万
Do you think they know you're... now 2 million
你是人面兽心
such a hypocrite?
曾先生现在出到210万
Good, Mr Tsang now bids 2.1 million
你这么乐善好施
Are you doing this
别人会看得到
to buy respectability?
你每举一次手
You know every time you bid,
我就损失20万 你知道吗
I lose 200 thou?
话不应该这么说
I don't agree
二十年来我为你赚了那么多
I helped you make so much money,
只是找个机会帮你花一点也很公道啊
now I'm helping you to spend it
这位坐轮椅的朋友出了240万
The guy in the wheelchair now bids 2.4 million
现在250万了 250万了
2.5 million, 2.5 million
你要再举手 这两只手都会报销
Big again, you'll lose your arms
260万 喔 好凶哦
2.6 million
周先生又锦上添花 270万
Oh, yes, yes, Mr Chow ups the bid to 2.7
有没有高过270万的没有
Any more than 2.7, 2.7 million
270万 一 270万 二 270万 三
Knock for the first time, knock for the second time
成交 谢谢周先生
Sold for the two point seven million
我代表儿童伤残协会谢谢慷慨大方的周先生
On behalf of the HK Handicapped Association
谢谢 周先生
Thank you Mr Chow, oh, right!
不好意思 不过我是故意的
Sorry, I did it on purpose
出去 你们干什么 你们想干什么
What do you want? What do you want?
警卫 你们不要杀我 我是伤残人士
Guards, help me. help me
大家镇定点 镇定点
Calm down. Calm down
麻烦清洁女工
Clean this mess up have the cleaning ladies
扫扫那些破瓷烂瓦
picked up these worthless ceramic pieces
哎 小心点 弄坏了你赔不起的
Hey, careful, you can't afford these
对不起 这里不准进去的
Sorry, this entrance is forbidden
对不起
Sorry
这位先生 请把通行证戴上
Please sir, put on your ID badge
哦 是 我忘了戴了 谢谢你
Sure, sorry I forget
各位 不要紧请冷静一点
Sir, is all right, all right, calm down
出去看看
Check it out
快把这些人疏散到外面去
Lead all the people out here
什么事啊
What happened? What happened?
隔壁那边发生了爆炸
An explosion there, "BANG"
还不关总开关
Get the fire extinguished, be quick
检查电路有没有问题
Turn off the mains
快去
Be quick
大师兄 老爸让你气的发火了
Brother, you made dad furious
你少在这里耍把戏
Don't play here,
这里轮不到你玩
this place is not for playing
我要发财的地方不许你出现
This is my turf, scram
不然你连轮椅都没得坐 走
If not, you can't even sit on a wheel chair
记着
Don't forget!
你看
Youlook
拍卖行保险库里的防盗系统
The auction house vault...
有十几个电脑程式
has more than 1O security systems
就算进的去 未必开得了
Even if you get to the vault, it may not open
那不是要抬个电脑进去
We may have to bring the whole computer inside
啊 那倒不必 只要里应外合
No, we just need good communications
喂 你们俩说什么呢
Hey, what are you two talking about?
占兄 你需要我的
James, do you need me?
哎 干爹
Papa
又想偷东西呀
You're going to steal again?
没有 打游戏机呢
We're playing computer games
拜托拜托 改邪归正吧
Well, I hope you two'll stick to the straight path
啊 你去煮饭吧
Go back and cook
是啊 你的围裙真性感
Hey, this apron looks "camp"
不正经
Be serious!
挺合身的
It suits you
OK 没问题
Alright, we got everything
万事俱备 我们先走就差保险库的钥匙 嗯
but the vault key
偷匙我去偷
Let me steal it
你没算我一份啊
What? Without me?
我一个人就行了
I think I can handle this
十几年兄弟 我不会坏你的事的
Brother, I won't cause you any trouble
哎 你已经瘸了腿
But you lost two leg already
我不希望你再没了手或者没了命
I don't want you to lose an arm of your life
哎 刚才聊的怎么样
What were you talking about?
你怎么越来越三八呀
Don't be so nosy
你们什么时候要小家伙呀
When do you want children?
想过了 想等做完这单再说
We thought about it, not till after this job though
要儿子要女儿
You want a boy or a girl?
我当然想先要儿子了
Of course a boy
她却想要女儿 说好带
But she wants a girl, easier to carry
取名了吗
Did you think of a name?
儿子呢就叫花贵仔
If it's a boy Joseph
女儿就叫聪明豆
If it's a girl Sherry
好啊 是不是要我做干爹呀
OK? Want me to be godfather?
这还用说 你不做干爹谁做干爹呀
Of course, who else?
想做干爹呢 你就要来美国
But you'll have to come to the State
是啊 我们想过些日子去美国 不回来了
We plan to settle over there
恭祝你生日快乐
Happy Birthday
来了 生日快乐
哇 好漂亮的蛋糕啊
Beautiful cake!
红豆亲自给你做的
Cherie made it for you
今天是你生日 你忘啦
Don't you remember today is your birthday
对了 我今年多大啦
Oh yeah, how old am I?
三十有六
Thirthy-six
哎哟 岁月催人老哇
Time sure goes by fast
哎 对了 把眼睛闭上
Close your eyes
干嘛
What for?
许愿呀
Make a wish
两个狡猾的狐狸
You're so fussy
你是不是没事啊
I told you there's no trick
相信你们好啦
Lucky for you
这个蛋糕太棒啦
The cake is delicious
谢谢
Thanks
喂 看那是谁
Hey, do you see him?
什么事
Who?
他就是拍卖行的主任 胡计修
He's the auction director, Stanley Wu
钥匙在他身上
He has the key,
不过 不知道放在哪
but don't know where he put it
以红豆的魅力
With Cherie's charm,
上去摸一摸不就知道了嘛
we'll be able to find out soon
真看得起我啊
What high praise
真兄 看来有人逼我跟你太太跳舞
Jim, can I dance with your wife?
请
Please
留意钥匙声
Listen for the key's noise
阿真
Dad
你是怎么搞的 带阿贵来会坏事
Bringing Joe here is asking for trouble
叙叙旧嘛 放心
Don't worry,
我保证帮你拿到那幅画
you'll get your painting
绝不能失手
You'll be responsible for him
你来干嘛
What are you doing here?
我来看我的儿子 你又来干嘛
I come to see my son, what are you doing?
我来看我儿子
I come to see my son too
看到啦
It's time to work
拜托 冷静点
Please do me a favour
胡主任
Mr Wu,
嗯
Oh, hello!
我是洛杉矶华人古董研究促进协会的代表
I'm the representative of the L.A. Chinese Antique Association
啊 幸会
Oh, hello!
我对古董文化很有兴趣
I'm keen on antique
我知道你是拍卖行主任
I know you are the auction director
你一定对古董很有研究
You must know a lot abut antiques
不敢当 我也是老古董啊
Well, actually I myself is an antique
我希望能够对历史文化作进一步的探讨
I want to do my thesis on Chinese culture and history
希望你指点一下晚辈
Would you show me the way please?
哎 亚占 你
Jim
阿真 你想干什么 又想偷
Jim, what are you doing here? Stealing again?
哎 你这么急上哪去
Hey, what's the hurry?
我的两个干儿子在聚旧而已嘛
They're just having a good time
来 我跟你喝一杯
Let's have a drink, come on
咱们俩都二十多年了 应该干一杯了吧
Don't you two think it's time for a drink? Come on
来跟我干爹喝一杯吧
Have a drink with Papa
我自己有
I got mine
1 2 3 4 5 6
1,2, 3,4, 5,6
喂 那里有事
Hey, something's going on there
哎 总台总台 开饭啦 收到了没有
Hello, Control, it's time to work,
开饭啦
can you hear me?
哎呀 老大 我收到了 你不必这么大声
Hey man, I can hear you, no need to shout
我耳朵聋了
Don't make me deaf
警卫回老家了 电闸房没锁门
The guards are off, they haven't locked the electricity room
想不到你的身手还是这么敏捷
I didn't think you're that good
不愧是我的最佳拍挡
No wonder we're partners
不要忘记我在空气中陪伴你
Don't forget I'll be with you
不要忘记在你最寂寞的时候
Whenever you get lonely,
我始终在你的耳边
I'll be the DJ in your ear
哎 总台 你鬼上身啦
Control what's gotten into you
怎么像跳大神的神婆
Are you possessed?
没问题 没问题
Don't worry...
你进了电闸房一定会看到很多的开关
As soon as you get into the electricity room,
你不必怕 也不必慌
Don't panic, you'll see lots of wires
看到了开关 一手按下去就行了
Once you find the switch, just switch it off
收到 开关按下啦 跟着又怎么样
Roger, the switch is off, what next?
啊 你真是机灵过机灵
You're not only smart,
聪明过聪明
but intelligent too
接下来你要告诉我线路的号码
Now give me the model number,
谢谢
please
JJ063 清不清楚
JJO63 OK?
萤光幕的显示呢 红色是代表危险的
According to the computer, the red one is dangerous
至于蓝色呢 是代表烦闷
The blue one has the blues
还有条黄色
As for the yellow one,
嚯 黄色是代表色情 是不能够剪的
can't cut that one, it's the sex one
那剪哪条才对啊
So which one do I cut?
蓝色 我最恨烦闷啦
The blue one, I hate the blues
剪啦
You got it
哦哦哦 剪啦就放心啦
I feel much better now
喂喂喂 我遇到麻烦啦
Oh, I saw a road block,
如果你按对了6个号码 那可不得了
if you push the right 6 numbers
中正六合彩 发大财
You'll win the grand price
什么号码
What no.?
等等啊
Hold on
五个8
Easy, first a 6, then five 8's
这个号码我买了很多期
I used these nos. a lot,
只是从来没有中过
but they never won
我会追的
So I keep on trying
行了吧 宝贝
Are you done yet, you one eyed trouser snake
行啦
Done
是吧 我就知道你能干嘛
Yeah? I knew you could do it, Sherlock
下次 太容易的事别找我做啊
Next time, don't ask me if it's so easy
什么 这话怎么说
Alright, whom should I ask?
太容易显得我低能
I'd introduced you to Watson
哎 现在轮到我啦 你拿听筒听听他的脉膊
Hey, stop joking, let me listen to the vault
转左32一次 转右15
Turn left to 32, right to 15
这么容易啊
is it really this easy?
转左13 停
Turn left to 13, stop
哎
YES!
接着呢 你就把听筒放低一点
Now put your stethoscope
让我听听下面的脉膊
on the lower lock
干什么
Then what?
喂 你怎么暂停啦
How can a DJ stop talking?
你想偷那幅画
You want to steal that painting?
嘘 这是直播节目
I'm on the air now
嗯 直播
Oh the air?
各位小朋友
Hello kids,
我们现在揭晓上一段谜语游戏的谜底
we have a riddle for you to solve
上一段谜面是馒头泡在稀饭里
Last riddle was: What room has no wall?
这谜底是什么呢
I'm going to tell you the answer now
就是周润发
The answer is MUSH-ROOM
我现在要跟低洼地区的听众说一说
Now for those who are not receiving us well,
如果你的收音机收得不太清晰呢
because you're far away like the New Territories
谢谢 请你转向80兆赫 对80兆赫
Please turn your radio to FM80, FM8O
要转两次才能够听得清楚
Turn twice to get a clearer reception
接着呢 要说的是
So what do we do now?
啊对 不要让它停
Of course we can't stop here
继续玩猜谜游戏啊
Must be riddle time again
下一个谜面是大家排队上厕所
Todays riddle is: What's pink and hides in a strawberry patch?
猜一个国家首都的名字
Can you guess the answer?
这谜底是什么呢 呃 一会大哥哥会向你揭晓的
Wait a bit, Bobo the clown will give you the answer
再见
That's all, bye
哎呀 你来得正是时候
You came just in time!
我在帮香港儿童成长基金
I'm helping HK Handicapped Children
做直播节目
do a charity broadcast
小朋友真可爱啊
They're really cute
我现在要去交水费 幸亏你来了
I gotta go bleed the lizard, I'm lucky you're here
你帮我顶一阵 我很快就回来
Can you help me, I'll be right back
幸亏你没去偷那幅画
Good thing you're not stealing the painting,
那里的保安系统改变啦
they changed the security system,
只要拿下画
as soon as you lift the painting
保险库的门就会自动关上
the vault door will automatically lock
哎 好啦好啦 哎 各位小朋友
Hello, Hi kids,
我就是那位大哥哥啦
I'm Bobo the clown
各位小朋友 我现在揭晓谜底啦
Well kids, here's the answer to the riddle
大家排队上厕所
Whats pink and hides in strawberry patches?
就是英国的首都 伦敦
A pink elephant
喂
Hello,
Hello.
阿贵 收到没有
Joe, are you there?
什么人 站住
Hey, hold it, don't move
阿真
Jim, Jim, Jim
阿真 坚持一下
Hold on
哎 怎么没炸呢 阿真
Why didn't it explode? Jim, damn it
糟糕 原来接错线了
Wrong connection
阿真吗 你听到没有 你答应我啊
Jim, are you alright, answer me
阿真
Jim, don't scare me
糟糕
Damn,
怎么搞的 没出错的嘛
it's all connected
阿真
Jim
啊 谢谢
Thanks
哎 你怎么有钥匙
How come you have the keys?
你怎么出来啦
How come you're here?
你炸这边 怎么那边开啦
You put the explosive here, so why did it explode on the other side?
啊 插错洞啦 我插错洞啦
Wrong socket. Wrong socket
你不相信啊
If you don't believe me,
你进去再让我再炸一次啊
I'll show you again
你怎么不进去让我炸啊
I dare not, let's go
真的啊 我一定成功的 再炸一次吧
Hey, I'm serious, get in, I'll show you
看见没有
Did you see them?
看见了
Yeah
是人是鬼啊
Are they people or ghost?
人啊
People
我顶
Let me head butt it
移形换影
Change position
我顶
I head butt it
走
Jump!
剩最后一颗炸弹啦 炸死他
Please grant me a bomb to kill this kid
又来啦
Not again?
大战之后 乃歌舞升平也
After war, time of peace come upon us
收工咯
Super
怎么样 昨天晚上没睡好啊
Dad, you didn't sleep all night?
这种情况下能睡得着 还是人吗 画呢
How could I? Where's my painting?
在我这里啊 如果你想拿回那幅画呢
With me, if you want it
就拿三千万来
give me 3O million for it
你这混蛋 敢这么跟老爸说话
You bastard, how can you talk to your dad like that?
我现在没兴趣说父子情
I don't want to talk family bullshit,
只有兴趣跟你谈生意
let's talk business
嗯 怎么谈
OK, how do you want it?
到我家来
Come to my place
这次去哪呀
Where to now?
日本 美国
Japan, States,
你喜欢去哪就去哪
wherever you want to go?
是不是真的啊
Really?
别到时候连你的影子都找不到
I hope you won't leave me standing again
嗱 你乖乖的在清水湾码头等我们
We'll come pick you up as soon as we're finished
我们办完事立刻去找你 嗯
Dear, you be Clear Water Bay pier
嗯 真的要来啊
You better!
老爸 老爸
Dad Dad
儿子 画呢
Son, where's the painting?
我们父子三人不是要变成这样吧
What happened to us?
没什么不对呀
What's wrong?
我们永远都不会忘记你的养育之恩的
I'll never forget you raised me, it's engraved in my heart!
我知道你们俩很乖
Jim, I know you are very filial,
我只想拿回那幅画
I just want my painting
是不是把画还给你
I'll give you the painting,
你就放我们一马
but you have to let us go
这幅画是我的命根子
That painting is my life,
你们肯把画还我 等于放我一马
if you give it back to me, I'll let you go
好说 您真仁慈 谢谢您给我们自由
You're so kind, thanks for giving us freedom
更多谢您放我们一马
Especially this chance
钱呢
The money?
我把你们养这么大 原来是养虎为患
I raised both of you, but I never thought you turn out so cruel
我要拿回你们欠我的
I'll exterminate you
不要啊
No please
阿贵
Joe
避弹衣 没事
It's bullet proof vest, so what?
没事啊 哈哈你骗我啊 装瘸子啊
Nothing, but aren't you limped?
如果不装瘸子
If I weren't limped,
你会让我参加吗
you won't be with me
如果不装瘸子
If I weren't limped,
我回来老爸早就把我宰啦
when I came back, dad would have killed me
是不是骗了很多你的感情
Did I made you sad...
很多的眼泪啊
and cry?
红豆那份怎么算啊
What about Cherie?
我会向她解释的 混球
I'll explain to her
喂 老爸呢
Where's dad?
你他妈的 真画在哪
You bastard, where's the real painting?
把他杀了 别弄坏那画
Kill him, don't spoil the painting
站好了 猴子 别动 晕不晕啊 好晕
stand. monkey. Hold it. Hold it.
要不要买保险
You want to buy any insurance?
买你的头
Go to hell!
BLACK JACK 庄家赢
Black Jack. The banker win
那么多A士 你还有A士吗
So many Ace, you must have AIDS
没有你多
Not as many as you
我帮你查查看
I'll check for you
你他妈的 我的衣服好贵的
Shit, you spoil my best suit
啊 香蕉水
It's corrosive fluid
啊 我喝了香蕉水
I drank the corrosive fluid
快叫救护车啊
Call the ambulance
善哉 善哉
Don't panic,
早就跟你说了不要玩火嘛
I asked you not to play with fire
我叫消防车来啊
Call the fire truck
不要动
Stop!
什么事干爹
What you want, dad?
上去拿画
Get the painting!
画上有电
But it's wired
快去 快
Go on
救火呀 快来救火呀 画完啦
Put it out, it's gone, it's gone
快来救火呀 快救火呀
The painting is gone, put it out
完啦 全完啦
Put it out, put it out, oh, no!
老爸 怎么样 很难受是吧
Dad, how is painful?
来 先坐下吧
Take a rest
我扶你 来
Let me help you
你们两个想杀我 没那么容易
You two want to kill me, not so easy
干爹
Papa
好 好 好
Alright, alright
你跟老爸好好聊一聊 交给你啦
Go and talk to dad for a while
每部电影的结尾都是坏人绳之于法
All movies have the bad guys caught at the end
这一部也不例外啊
This movie is no exception
包涵包涵 啊
Smile, hey
给我站住
Don't move
就这么走啦
You intend to leave like this?
我们都大义灭亲了
We caught him for justice
您又遂了心愿 不走干嘛
And your wish come true, what's the point of staying?
哎 我是警察
Clean this mess up first
怎么样呢
What do you mean?
你们要这么走
I'm a police officer
那我不是很没面子吗
I can't let you go, that's illegal
我打不下手啊
I can't do this
哎 儿子打老爸 天打雷劈的
Patricide is punishable by death
天打雷劈的
Yeah, die young
哎 那那 我先把眼睛闭上
Huh, alright, that's enough out of you two
你们打吧
I close my eyes
你打
Hit him
你打吧
Hey, hit him
你来打吧
Go on, hit
还是你打吧
Alright, here I go
快打啊
OK
好
Don't hit the forehead
那我打了啊
Hit the temple
来了啊 真的啊
OK, here I go
忍着点啊
Get ready
嗯 很痛的喔 嗯
It'll hurt
已经走啦
They're gone already, dumb jerks
红豆
Cherie
阿真 阿海呢
Jim, where's Joe?
红豆妹妹
Cherie
大胖妞
Honey bunch
腿不瘸了吗
You can walk?
瘸着腿我怎么逃亡呢
If I'm limping, how can I run away?
哦哦 你又耍我 你好坏啊
Ah, so you lied to me, you bastard
哎哎 不要玩啦 不要玩啦
Alright, enough. enough.
没什么送给你的
You're in a rush,
送盒贵糕给你们吃 再见
I got nothing for you, except for this fruit cake, bye
不是说好一起走吗
Aren't we leaving together?
怎么了你
Right,
不是说好了同甘共苦的嘛
didn't we say we'll always be together
哎 吉姆兄 话不能这么说啊
Jim, well, not exactly
正所谓天下无不散之筵席
Every good thing has to end some time
况且我喜欢浪迹天涯 孤身上路
In fact, I prefer traveling alone, footloose and carefree
以后好好照顾红豆啊
Take good care of Cherie
你又搞什么啊
What do you mean?
保重
Take care
怎么搞的
What do we do?
我走啦 祝你们俩个春梦了无痕吶
I'm leaving, I wish you all the best
阿贵
Joe
啊 是怎么样啊 怎么样
Yes, well, what do you want?
不是一定要留你
We don't mean you must stay
不过你说过的话要算数
But don't you think a promise must be kept
我说过什么话啦我
What did I promise?
你答应过做我孩子的干爹
You promised to be godfather to our kids, remember?
那是随便那么一说嘛
That was a long time ago
而且馅儿都有啦
Well, Cherie is pregnant now
嗯 真难听
Hey, stop that
这么不小心哪
Mustn't forget the condoms!
来不来啊
Are you coming?
别烦我啊
Sure you don't want to come
好 开船
Alright, cast off
哎 等一等 我来解缆绳
Stop, wait for me
现在这幅画呢
So where is the painting?
完璧归赵啦
Back home
做饭去
Go back to work.